# **Muhammad Adeel Arshad**

## Lahore, Pakistan +923456490263

<u>muhammadadeelarshed@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/adeelarshad1997/</u>

### **Summary**

I have about 5 years of experience in software development, mainly focusing on web application development working with React, NextJs TypeScript, NestJs, AWS Serverless, HTML5, CSS3, SQL, GraphQL, Microservices, and Cloud Platforms (AWS, GCP, Azure). I mainly work in the EST timezone.

I am very passionate about learning new industry trends, resolving challenges, and working in an agile work environment.

### Education

**Bachelor's degree, Computer Science | COMSATS University Lahore** 01/2017 - 12/2020

## **Experience**

Senior Software Engineer | Iron Mountain (Remote)

Aug 2023 – Present, Boston, Massachusetts

- I improved Iron Mountain's product development infrastructure as a core team player.
- AWS Serverless Backend, which I mostly focused on, based on AWS( Step Functions, AppSync, DynamoDB, TimeStream, Pipelines, CodeBuild)
- The responsibilities on the front end side are to manage the micro front end modules using module federation web pack 5
- **Skills**: Next.js, React.js, NEST.JS, React Hooks, Redux, AWS Amplify, AWS step-functions, AWS Lambda, AWS DynamoDB, GraphQL, Cypress, Jest, Agile/Scrum

**Tech Lead & Senior Developer** | Virus Geeks (Remote)

FEB 2022 - JULY 2023, LAHORE

- Participated in analysis, designing, development, unit test, code review & deployment process
- Documented code changes to existing functionalities or new requirements raised in the design doc

- Coordinated with QA Engineer & performed code changes, closely worked with Product Manager
- Utilized in-depth knowledge of concepts & procedures within own area and basic knowledge of other areas to resolve the issue
- Building a website for a Medical portal for patients, doctors, and lab technicians.
- Skills: Next.js, Angular.Js, React Hooks, Redux, NEST.JS, PostgreSQL, typeORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, Cypress, Jest, Agile/Scrum

### **Senior Software Engineer** | Focusteck

Jun 2022 – Jan 2023, Lahore

- Web application development using Angular JS & NestJS
- Technically guiding other team members & analyzing test execution
- Defects are assigned on priority to each offshore engineer & tracked regularly
- **Skills**: Next.js, React.js, Angular.Js, React Hooks, Redux, NEST.JS, PostgreSQL, typeORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, Cypress, Jest, Agile/Scrum

### **Senior MERN Developer** | TechmateTech LLC.

May 2021 - July 2022, Lahore

- As a MERN stack developer, my responsibility is to make software that customizes the UI and UX of any Web application through just simple clicks and taps.
- Build a web App that will help the chef collect orders and manage them
- Worked on bug fixing and improving application performance
- Worked with other team members to implement design requirements for a project

Skills: Next.js, NEST.js, ReactNative, Redux, NEST.JS, MongoDB, Circle Cl Jest

#### **Full Stack Engineer** | AMOXT Solutions Inc.

Jan 2020 - May 2021, Lahore

- Building Mass video production tool using Nest JS with Nats & Redis on backend and NextJS on frontend
- Utilized Agile methodology to develop a software application
- Worked on bug fixing and improving application performance
- Worked with other team members to implement design requirements for a project
- Skills: Next.js, NEST.js, React Hooks, Redux, NEST.JS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Cypress, Jest

#### **SKILLS**

- TypeScript, JavaScript (ES6+)
- React.js, Next.js, React Native
- Redux, Thunk, Saga
- React Hooks, React Context

- Node.js, Express, NestJS
- Microservice, RESTful API
- TypeORM, Sequelize, Prisma
- GraphQL, Apollo, JSON, XML

- MUI, Styled Components
- jQuery, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS
- MERN, MEAN
- Jest, Cypress, Enzyme
- Jasmine, Jest, Mocha
- Webpack, Browserfy, NPM
- Ethers.js, Web3.js

- Socket.io, WebSocket
- Elasticsearch, Redis
- Twilio, Stripe, oAuth
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL
- AWS Lambda, S3, DynamoDB, EC2
- GCP, Azure, Heroku, Firebase
- Docker, Docker Compose
- Jenkins, CircleCI, Travis CI